[

](https://bearable.app/)

---------------------------------

Menu

#### Privacy Policy

##### Last updated 8th July 2022.  
_Updated to clarify that as a UK company,_ we’re not required to have to comply with US criminal subpoenas requesting disclosure of data.

**Before reading our Privacy Policy** there are a few things that we think are especially important for our users to understand about how we manage their data.

1. Bearable does not and will never sell any personal data. We made this app primarily to help people like us and this would not be in line with our values.

2\. Bearable does not track or share any personal data with third party companies unless you specifically choose to enable that option (e.g. with Google Fit or Apple Health).

3\. To protect your privacy, any health data that you choose to track for your own purposes is encrypted before it is backed up on our servers.

4\. Bearable is compliant with GDPR and other data handling policies and practices.

5\. Bearable tracks as little personally identifiable data as possible to protect its users. We purposefully do not ask for information like Name, Age, Sex, and Gender so as to improve user privacy.

We recognise the sensitive nature of the health and personal data that you choose to track with Bearable and strongly believe in the importance of data security, privacy, and anonymity.  We take your privacy seriously and we hope that you find our privacy policy clear and transparent. 

Introduction

This privacy statement explains how we, BEARABLE Limited (“Bearable”, “us”, “we” or “our”) use your personal data to provide you with the Bearable mobile application (The “Bearable App”) and website (www.bearable.app).

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. We ask that you read this Privacy Statement carefully as it contains important information about what personal data we collect from you and how we will use it. Any questions you may have regarding this Privacy Statement are welcomed and should be sent to [support@bearable.app](mailto:support@bearable.app).

This Privacy Statement should be read in conjunction with our [Terms & Conditions](http://bearable.app/terms-and-conditions/). We strongly encourage you to review this Privacy Statement and Terms & Conditions carefully and ensure that they contain nothing that you are not prepared to agree to, before you decide to accept the Terms & Conditions and use our Bearable App or our website ([www.bearable.app](http://bearable.app/)).

About us

BEARABLE Limited is a company registered in England and Wales with company registration number 12089632. Our registered office is at Elite House, 155 Main Road, Biggin Hill, Kent, England, TN16 3JP.  We are registered with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office and our registration number is ZB189459.  

For the purpose of the EU General Data Protection Regulation, the UK General Data Protection Regulation and the Data Protection Act 2018 (together “Data Protection Legislation”), we are the ‘data controller’ (i.e. the company which determines the purposes and means of the processing of your personal data).

Bearable has appointed a Data Protection Officer, who can be contacted at  support@bearable.app.

How we process your data at bearable

To register an account, you have to enter your email address and choose a password.  You may also register using a Google Account, Apple Account or Facebook.  Once you have registered, you will benefit from the following functionality:

* * Access to platform to view any data that you choose to submit
    * Automatic backup to our secure servers. as well as the ability to restore and recover your account and it’s associated data on another device

There are **two main purposes** for which we process personal data and the type of data that is processed to fulfil each purpose:

**1\. To provide our services and understand your needs**
=========================================================

First and foremost it is vital for us to stress that we do not and will never sell any personal data about you to third parties.  However you may still feel uncomfortable storing health information to a connected device.  Therefore, you should consider the safety and privacy of your personal data before using the Bearable app generally, and utilising the export feature of the app specifically.  You should refrain from sharing or exporting data unless you are certain that the receiving email address is authorised, credible, and secure.

When you use the Bearable app, or when you go on our website, Bearable collects, stores, and uses some personal data (e.g. your email address).  We mainly do this to verify you as a user so that we can provide you with our services and to send you service messages by email, and our lawful basis for this processing is that it is necessary for the performance of a contract with you (i.e. our Terms and Conditions).

We may also occasionally send you marketing and promotional messages as well as reminders to your smartphone via push notifications.  We will only send you such messages with your prior consent.

We are very thoughtful and selective about what we communicate and how often. You always remain in full control of your communication preferences with Bearable. You can change the settings within the app at anytime.

We also process your personal data and non-personal data in order to understand your needs and your use of our app and website, to analyze bugs and fix issues, and to bring you more useful features.  To sum it up, we process this data to provide you the best and most reliable experience of our services and we aim for it to be as anonymised as possible.  These processing activities are based on our legitimate interests in providing a reliable service to you, and improving it or on your consent where you have opted in by accepting the use of certain cookies on our app or website.

These are the types of data we collect for the above purposes:

**Device data**  
This data informs us about the device you use to access our services, such as the model, name and identifiers, device settings, the application identifier, and crash information. On our website, we collect information about your browser and browser settings, the operating system you use, and the system settings of your device.

**Event and usage data**  
When you use the app or when you go our website, our servers process anonymised data in order to understand your usage of our services, for example, which pages you visit or which tab in the app you open. We collect this information and use it as aggregate data to allow us to better understand which features are the most relevant or useful to our users as whole, and to communicate with you about relevant and timely information and promotional content.

**IP address**  
Through our use of cookies (see below) and if you consent, we collect IP addresses provided by your browser or mobile device to deliver the service to your device. We also use the IP address to determine your approximate location for statistical and analytics purposes.

The amount we collect has been minimised wherever possible to respect your privacy.

**2\. To deliver personalised insights** 
=========================================

The data you track in Bearable about your health and activities is considered _sensitive personal data_.  Bearable does not store sensitive personal data without your explicit consent.  It is only when you give us explicit consent by creating a Bearable account, and giving us your consent declaration, that we start storing  health data that you choose to provide  on our secured servers.

You can withdraw your consent at any time by simply deleting your account in the app. 

Here is the type of data we collect and store when you create an account:

**Personal data used for account creation**  
We need some of your personal data (only your email address) in order to create your Bearable account.

**Health and sensitive data**  
With your consent, we store health data, such as your mood, energy levels and individual symptom levels, your medication and supplements and other health factors you track in the app (e.g. sleep quality, exercise, diet and food diary, general daily activities such as work, tv, grocery shopping etc.).  

The provision of this information is entirely voluntary, and it is up to you how much information to input.

You may also allow us to connect to third-party services, such as Apple HealthKit and Google Fit, to enable us to import Personal Data about your health and activities into the App. This imported data may include activity level, weight, calories burned, heart rate, sleep, blood pressure, blood glucose,  temperature, number of steps/distance travelled, and other data about your health. We will process this data in order to provide you with the App functionality described below.  When you choose to have this data imported you are subject to the Google Fit and Apple HealthKit privacy policies and practices. 

It’s important to clarify that your health data is encrypted on our services and the only personal data it is attached to is your email address. 

**Principles of Processing**
============================

**Data minimization and purpose limitation.** We will not process Personal Data in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by you or collect any Personal Data that is not needed for the mentioned purposes. For any new purpose of processing we will ask your separate consent. 

**No sale of Personal Data.** We will not sell or rent your Personal Data. We will not disclose your Personal Data except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. We may share your Personal Data with our service providers solely as described in this Privacy Policy. We will also not use information received through your use of the HealthKit and Google Fit framework for advertising or similar services, or sell it to advertising platforms, data brokers, or information resellers.

Your consent for processing health and sensitive data

If you create an account with Bearable, your personal data, including sensitive data and data related to your health, is stored on your device and is also stored and processed on Bearable servers. This is done so we can offer you the option of backing up your data and to enable additional features (such as the ability to transfer, restore, and recover data between Apple and Android devices).

By creating an account with Bearable you explicitly consent that:

**i. Bearable may store and process personal data you provide through the usage of the Bearable app and through the account creation process solely for the purpose of providing Bearable services to you and to improve Bearable’s service features. Such Bearable services may include sending you information and reminders through the Bearable app, e.g. via push notification or to the email address you provided to Bearable, where you have separately agreed to receive such messages.**

**ii. Such personal data you provide to Bearable through the account creation process for the purpose of providing Bearable’s service includes personal data you enter into the Bearable app, such as your account data (e.g. your email address), and your health data which may include your mood levels and individual symptom levels, your medication and supplements and other health factors you track in the app (e.g. sleep quality, exercise, diet and food diary, general daily activities such as work, tv, meditation etc.).   All of your health data is encrypted on the server end.**

You may withdraw your consent to this use of your data at any time by deleting your Bearable account.  This can be requested by e-mailing [support@bearable.app](mailto:support@bearable.app).  You can also delete your data from the settings page within the Bearable App at any time.

Your rights

We believe that data privacy is a [basic human right](http://www.ohchr.org/EN/Issues/DigitalAge/Pages/DigitalAgeIndex.aspx). At BEARABLE we strive to ensure that your rights are respected.

Here are some key facts about your privacy that we would like you to know:

i. Our services have been designed to minimise the use of your personal data. We only collect and process your personal data for the purposes that have been previously outlined.

ii. Your data is highly secured on our servers (using the Firestore database, which encrypts all of your data, as seen [here](https://cloud.google.com/firestore/docs/server-side-encryption) to protect your data from unauthorized access). You can contact us at [support@bearable.app](mailto:support@bearable.app) if you have any questions about the security of our services.

iii. We do not retain your personal data in an identifiable format for longer than necessary to deliver our services.  As soon as we can, we encrypt your email address and create an anonymised user ID so that your health data is not directly connected to your email address on our systems.  

iv. Bearable does not engage in any automated decision-making or profiling activities.

As a user of Bearable’s services and website, you may exercise your user rights to:

i. Request information on, or a copy of, your personal data processed by Bearable. Upon your request, this information will be provided to you electronically.

ii. Gain access to your personal data by requesting a backup of your data (as explained in the next section) in a format that is readable by other companies or organisations (data portability).

iii. Correct your personal data and health data in the app settings and in the tracking categories available in the Bearable app.

iv. Withdraw your consent from data processing at any time by deleting your account (as explained in the support section of the app) and/or deleting the Bearable app from your smartphone, and/or unsubscribing from our newsletter by clicking the link at bottom of the email or by contacting [support@bearable.app](mailto:james@bearable.app).

v. Request the complete deletion of your data, including all past data sent to third-party services used for tracking and analysis, by reaching out to [support@bearable.app](mailto:james@bearable.app) Your data will be deleted as soon as possible and within 30 days.

vi. Object to our processing of your personal data, or ask us to restrict your personal data pending a decision on whether we can lawfully continue to process it.

vii. File a complaint with the relevant supervising authority (such as the UK Information Commissioner’s Office if you are based in the UK or if you are a resident of California, the California Privacy Protection Agency) if you believe Bearable is processing your personal data under violation of applicable data protection regulations.

Data Security

We apply security measures to protect against the misuse, loss, and/or alteration of personal data under our control.  Though we cannot ensure or guarantee that misuse, loss or alteration of information will never occur, we use all reasonable efforts to prevent it and keep our security methods and systems under close review.  Although we make good faith efforts to store all personal information entered into the App in a secure operating environment that is not available to the public, we cannot guarantee complete security. We cannot and do not guarantee that our security measures will prevent third party “hackers” from illegally accessing our site or App and obtaining access to content or information thereon.

**How Bearable stores your personal data**
==========================================

If you have an account with Bearable, your personal profile data (email address) is stored separately from your health (mood, symptoms, medication, your customised health factors) data and your service settings. This allows us to ensure the highest possible level of privacy for your health data. Your password is stored using one-way encryption (“hashing” plus “salting”).

Your data is transmitted between your device and Bearable’s servers using the HTTPS protocol for encryption. HTTPS is the same technology used to create secure connections for your web browser and is indicated by a padlock icon in the URL bar of your browser.

**Disclosure of your personal data** 
=====================================

We will share some of your personal data with third parties outside Bearable only where it is strictly necessary to provide our services to you, where required by law, where we have another legitimate interest to do so or where you specifically consent to it.  We will always seek legal advice prior to sharing this data and would always seek to disclose the minimum information necessary.  Personal data may be shared in the following circumstances:

* Third Party Support Service Providers: For example: technology service providers, payment providers, data storage providers, and marketing platforms (e.g. for sending marketing emails),
* Third Party Apps: some of your personal data may be shared with other Apps but only if you agree to that.  Please see the section below for further information.
* When required to do so by law, regulation or court order;
* in response to a legitimate request for assistance by the police or other law enforcement agency. 
* Please note that as a UK company, we’re not required to have to comply with US criminal subpoenas requesting disclosure of data, in light of Roe v Wade.
* to seek legal advice from Bearable’s external lawyers or in connection with litigation with a third party; or
* in connection with the sale, purchase or merger of our business. 

**Bearable’s recommendations for protecting your personal data**
================================================================

We believe the biggest threat to the security and privacy of your personal data is if someone, probably someone you know, gains access to any of your devices. The data you enter into Bearable is private and it should stay that way. We have outlined some ways to keep your devices secure below.

**Protect your device:**  
i. Activate either PIN, TouchID (iPhone 5S models onwards), or FaceID (iPhone X onwards) authentication for your device. This automatically encrypts your Bearable data and prevents any person from using your device without your permission.

ii. Set up a feature that will allow you to erase all the data from your device if it’s been lost or stolen. For iOS, activating this feature is a two-step process: first, you need to Activate “Find My iPhone” via iCloud (see instructions on [Apple Support pages](https://support.apple.com/en-ca/explore/find-my-iphone-ipad-mac-watch)) and then enable “Erase your device” (see instructions on [Apple Support pages](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph2701?locale=en_GB)).

For Android, download and set up [Find My Device](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.adm&hl=en) (formerly Android Device Manager) from the Google Play Store and, if needed, use the connected [web interface](https://www.google.com/android/find) to lock or wipe your phone remotely.

DATA TRANSFER OUTSIDE THE UK or THE EU

Any personal data we collect from you may only be transferred to countries outside the United Kingdom or the European Economic Area (EEA) observing applicable privacy regulations and ensuring that your privacy rights remain protected. This includes ensuring that all such transfers are subject to approved safeguards which meet the requirements of Data Protection Legislation (for example, through the use of EU Commission or UK ICO approved standard contractual clauses).

**Data transfer to third party service providers**
==================================================

We may transfer personal data to third party service providers who support our business as follows:  

**Google Firebase**
===================

In the Bearable App we use Firebase ([https://www.firebase.com/](https://www.firebase.com/)), a framework maintained by the Google subsidiary Firebase residing in San Francisco, CA, USA, through which we use to track and administer the following real-time functions:

1\. Tracking of basic user events for Firebase  
2\. User Authentication  
3\. Database Storage  
4\. Tracking of app crashes and their reasons through Firebase

**Crashlytics**
===============

For all mentioned Firebase services, only anonymized or pseudonymized user data is transmitted to Firebase (Google).

Firebase’s privacy policy is available under [https://www.firebase.com/terms/privacy-policy.html](https://www.firebase.com/terms/privacy-policy.html)

We use Firebase Crashlytics to track app crashes as they occur, and to prevent future ones. In case of an app crash, a report is created that contains the type and OS of the device, your last activities in the app, and your geolocation in pseudonymous form, and that is sent to Google.

Information on the functionality of Crashlytics is available under [https://firebase.google.com/products/crashlytics/](https://firebase.google.com/products/crashlytics/)

We use Firebase Authentication to allow you to sign up and log in – Most apps need to know the identity of a user. Knowing your identity allows us to securely save user data in the cloud and provide the same personalized experience across all of the your devices.  
Your data is safely stored on the secure Firestore database, which automatically encrypts all data before it is stored, as can be read here.

The location of our Firestore is EU-West3 (Frankfurt, Germany).

The Google Privacy Policy is available at [https://policies.google.com/privacy.](https://policies.google.com/privacy.)

For more information on app crash data, go to the information provided by Crashlytics at [https://try.crashlytics.com/terms/privacy-policy.pdf.](https://try.crashlytics.com/terms/privacy-policy.pdf.)

**Facebook/Google/Apple Logins**
================================

Bearable enables Facebook/Google/Apple Logins to allow our users to create and log in to their Bearable account with their Facebook/Google/Apple credentials. If you sign up for Bearable using one of these platforms, you authorise us to collect your basic profile information available via that platform such as your name and email address. This information is collected by the platform and is provided to us under the terms of their own privacy policy. You can control the data we receive from Facebook/Google/Apple in the privacy settings within your Facebook/Google/Apple account.

Please refer to the privacy policy of the respective platform for more detail about the way in which these platforms collect and use your personal data.    

**Segment**
===========

The Bearable App uses Segment, a data platform offered by Segment.io, Inc, 100 California St #700, San Francisco, CA 94111, United States. We use the Segment data platform to securely pass data between platforms such as the Bearable App and Google Analytics. This enables us to unify customer data across touchpoints on different platforms such as our website and app. So that we can optimize, personalize, and improve the experiences and services that we provide to our users. Segment data is encrypted at rest and protected by TLS in transit. Segment’s Data Processing Agreement (DPA) and Privacy Policy reflects the requirements of the GDPR… The Segment libraries generate an anonymous Id for each user. An anonymous Id is a randomly generated 36 character string automatically assigned to a user on their first visit to a website or mobile application. The anonymous Id links events performed by the user as they navigate around the Bearable app, website, and other touchpoints such as emails and push notifications.

More information is available at: [https://segment.com/legal/privacy/](https://segment.com/legal/privacy/)

**Zendesk**
===========

Like many businesses, we use Zendesk to assist with customer support.  

More information available here: https://www.zendesk.co.uk/company/privacy-and-data-protection/

**Moosend**
===========

We use the mailing tool “Moosend” and the associated interface(s), a service of the provider Sitecore USA Inc., 101 California Street, Suite 1600, San Francisco, CA 94111, USA. When registering for our platform and services,, the following data will be processed via Moosend’s servers: e-mail address, browser information, subscription status, IP address, data about interactions with e-mails from Moosend.  

We consider Moosend to be a third party data processor. The email address that you submit will not be stored within this website’s own database or in any of our internal computer systems.

Your email address will remain within Moosend’s database for as long as we continue to use Moosend’s services for email marketing (and service emails) or until you specifically request removal from the list. To do this click on the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.

The details of the data collected and handled by the Moosend platform can be found here:  [https://www.sitecore.com/trust/privacy-policy](https://www.sitecore.com/trust/privacy-policy) in their privacy statement. 

**Data transfer to third party apps:**
======================================

We may transfer personal data to third party apps if you choose to enable this option: 

**Apple Health (iOS)**
======================

Bearable will not exchange any personal data with Apple’s Health Kit app without your prior approval. Approval is given by you in the relevant settings of the Health Kit app or within the Bearable app during initial user profile setup or via app settings and can be revoked by you at any time. If you have given your approval, Bearable may interact with the Health Kit app on your iOS device and read information from it, such as Steps, Sleep, Blood Pressure, Heart Rate and Weight data. This may include a transfer of your personal data to Apple servers located outside the UK or the European Economic Area.

You can choose if and to what extent your personal data is exchanged between Bearable and the Health Kit app by granting or revoking appropriate permissions in the Health Kit app settings. Please refer to the Privacy Information of Apple Health for further information about how Apple treats your personal data.

For more information about Apple’s privacy policy visit: [https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/](https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy/en-ww/)

**Google Fit**
==============

Bearable will not exchange any personal data with Google Fit without your prior approval, such approval is given by you in the relevant settings of Google Fit or within the Bearable app during initial user profile setup or via app settings and which can be revoked by you at any time. If you have given your approval, Bearable may interact with Google Fit on your Android device and read information from it, such as Steps, Sleep, Blood Pressure, Heart Rate and Weight data. This may include a transfer of your personal data to Google servers located outside the UK or the European Economic Area.

You can choose whether or not your personal data is exchanged between Bearable and Google Fit by granting or revoking appropriate permissions in Google Fit settings.

Bearable’s use and transfer to any other app of information received from Google APIs will adhere to [Google API Services User Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use requirements.

Please refer to the Privacy Information of Google Fit for further information.

More information is available at: [https://www.google.com/fit/](https://www.google.com/fit/) & [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) (general information on Google Analytics and data protection).

Cookies, Tracking and Payment data

With your consent our website uses certain non-essential cookies, which are small text files that are intended to make the site better for you to use. In general, cookies are used to retain preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide tracking data to third-party applications like Google Analytics. You may, however, disable cookies on Bearable’s site. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the help section of your browser or doing your own web research on how to disable cookies. In the meantime, here is a short guide to help:

1. Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies—for example:  
    1. in Internet Explorer (version 10) you can block cookies using the cookie handling override settings available by clicking “Tools,” “Internet Options,” “Privacy,” and then “Advanced”;
    2. in Firefox (version 24) you can block all cookies by clicking “Tools,” “Options,” “Privacy,” selecting “Use custom settings for history” from the drop-down menu, and unticking “Accept cookies from sites”; and
    3. in Chrome (version 29), you can block all cookies by accessing the “Customize and control” menu, and clicking “Settings,” “Show advanced settings,” and “Content settings,” and then selecting “Block sites from setting any data” under the “Cookies” heading.
2. Blocking all cookies will have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use all the features on our website.
3. You can delete cookies already stored on your computer—for example:  
    1. in Internet Explorer (version 10), you must manually delete cookie files (you can find instructions for doing so at [http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835](http://support.microsoft.com/kb/278835) );
    2. in Firefox (version 24), you can delete cookies by clicking “Tools,” “Options,” and “Privacy”, then selecting “Use custom settings for history”, clicking “Show Cookies,” and then clicking “Remove All Cookies”; and
    3. in Chrome (version 29), you can delete all cookies by accessing the “Customize and control” menu, and clicking “Settings,” “Show advanced settings,” and “Clear browsing data,” and then selecting “Delete cookies and other site and plug-in data” before clicking “Clear browsing data.”

We obtain your consent before we use any non-essential cookies on your device when you choose to access our website.  You may withdraw your consent at any time, by either disabling cookies on your device or following the instructions on how to withdraw your consent individually for each third party provider Bearable uses for its third party tracking and analysis services.

For the purpose of tracking the performance of our services and to improve Bearable services Bearable uses the following third party services:

**Google Analytics**
====================

Our website and mobile app both use [Google Analytics](https://google.com/analytics),  an analysis service operated by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies (text files) stored on your computer to allow for anonymous analysis of your website and mobile app use and interactions with both (for example what screens you are visiting most in the Bearable App) in order to personalize your experience and improve our services. Information produced via cookies will be transferred to and stored on a server in the USA operated by Google.  We use Google Analytics on our website and mobile app to recognize a computer when a user visits the website or users the mobile app, track users as they navigate the website or mobile app, improve the website and mobile app’s usability, analyze the use of the website and mobile app, administer the website and mobile app, prevent fraud and improve the security of the website.

Google analyzes this information to offer reports for Bearable on website usage and online usage of associated services. Google may also transfer this information to third parties either when this is required by law or when third parties are contracted by Google to process this data. Google will not allow your IP address to be linked to any other personal data. You can prevent cookies from being stored on your computer by changing your browser settings; however, if you choose to do this, your experience when visiting our website or using some of our features may be altered.

By using Bearable’s website, you consent to have non-personal data used and processed by Google as described above. You can withdraw consent for this use of your data at any time, but this withdrawal only applies to future activities.

**Mixpanel**
============

For the Bearable App itself, we use Mixpanel, a third-party application analytics service, to collect data from real-world application usage that is used to improve the Bearable product — for example, to determine frequency of usage of particular product features.  None of the data that is run through Mixpanel is attached to any personally identifiable information.

Mixpanel is a third-party application analytics service operated by Mixpanel Inc, a company headquartered in San Francisco Bay Area in Western United States.  Their privacy policy can be found [here](https://mixpanel.com/legal/privacy-policy/).

**RevenueCat**
==============

The App uses [RevenueCat](https://revenuecat.com/) to manage trial versions and paid subscriptions. RevenueCat’s Privacy Policy can be [found here](https://www.revenuecat.com/privacy).

———————————

The above mentioned companies are either EU-based or have put in place appropriate safeguards to ensure that UK or European data privacy requirements are met. The privacy policy of these services can be found on their respective websites.

**AppsFlyer**
=============

The Bearable App uses AppsFlyer, an analysis service offered by AppsFlyer Inc, 111 New Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105. We use the AppsFlyer tracking software to measure the success of our marketing campaigns. AppsFlyer collects and stores data on how the website is used by applying pseudonyms. The user profiles thus compiled serve to analyse user patterns and are used to improve and customise our offers. The service may use cookies which we may use where we have your consent to do so. The pseudonymised user profiles are not associated with personal data pertaining to the holder of the pseudonym, unless the user explicitly gives his or her consent in a separate procedure.

You can object to the future collection and storage of your data by AppsFlyer at any time by following the corresponding instructions at [https://www.appsflyer.com/optout.](https://www.appsflyer.com/optout.)

Facebook  

In our app, we use the Software Development Kit (SDK) from Facebook Inc. (Facebook), 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA. 

In Bearable’s mobile application (App), we use the Software Development Kit (SDK) from Facebook Inc. (Facebook).   This helps us to understand the success of our advertising campaigns, and to target our advertising more effectively.  When you use the App, we will share the following anonymised data with Facebook:  anonymous Facebook ID, advertiser IDs, and anonymised Bearable ID.

By using the App, you consent to have non-personal data used and processed by Facebook as described above.

You can find out more information about the Facebook SDK under iOS at [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/ios](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/ios). For Android here: [https://developers.facebook.com/docs/and](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/and).  

You can withdraw your consent to use of this cookie at any time, however you will be unable to use the App.  

Marketing, Communications, Surveys and newsletter activities

Bearable uses your personal data, such as your email address, to contact you with messages, emails, and newsletters. These may include push notifications, in-app messages and emails to deliver health content and occasional promotional materials that may be of interest to you.

Such services are only provided to you if you have signed up specifically to receive them. You consent to push notifications when you activate Bearable’s push notifications in your device settings.  You can withdraw this consent at any time.  You can unsubscribe from our newsletter by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the message, and you can disable marketing notifications sent by Bearable in your device settings.

Whether or not you have provided any consent, Bearable may need to contact you in respect of our service (e.g. to explain how it operates) or to respond to a question if you have contacted Bearable with questions or support requests in connection with our services or the Bearable app. These are known as “service emails” and do not require your consent.  Rather, we send them on the basis of legitimate interest.  

Also on the basis of legitimate interest, Bearable may request survey responses to receive your feedback, e.g. on the performance of the app or on certain health topics. Such information given by you via such surveys is processed by Bearable for the purposes as set forth in this privacy policy. 

**Moosend**
===========

We use the mailing tool “Moosend” and the associated interface(s), a service of the provider Sitecore USA Inc., 101 California Street, Suite 1600, San Francisco, CA 94111, USA. When registering for our platform and services,, the following data will be processed via Moosend’s servers: e-mail address, browser information, subscription status, IP address, data about interactions with e-mails from Moosend.  

We consider Moosend to be a third party data processor. The email address that you submit will not be stored within this website’s own database or in any of our internal computer systems.

Your email address will remain within Moosend’s database for as long as we continue to use Moosend’s services for email marketing (and service emails) or until you specifically request removal from the list. To do this click on the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email. When requesting removal via email, please send your email to us using the email account that is subscribed to the mailing list.

The details of the data collected and handled by the Moosend platform can be found here:  [https://www.sitecore.com/trust/privacy-policy](https://www.sitecore.com/trust/privacy-policy) in their privacy statement. 

**Lookalike Audiences**
=======================

For advertising purposes, we occasionally use information about our customers to generate a “[lookalike audience](https://www.facebook.com/business/help/164749007013531)” or [similar audience](https://support.google.com/adwords/answer/2676774) of prospective customers through the Facebook or Google advertising platforms. This allows us to show advertisements on their networks to potential customers who appear to have shared interests or similar demographics to our existing customers, based on the platforms’ own data.

We typically do this by sharing email data with Facebook using [Segment](https://segment.com/) or directly via the [Facebook SDK](https://developers.facebook.com/docs/) so as to process this data as securely as possible. [Facebook’s policy](https://www.facebook.com/business/help/112061095610075/) is to irreversibly hash (encrypt) such lists prior to uploading, match the hashed data against their own customers, generate the lookalike audience, then delete the uploaded list and use it for no other purpose.

We do not have access to the identity of anybody in the lookalike audience unless they choose to click on the ads. Based on this, we believe that generating lookalike audiences poses little or no threat to the privacy of our customers. If you wish to opt-out of “similar audiences” in Google, you can do so through your [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

Young users

This service is not intended for children under the age of 16.  Bearable does not knowingly collect or use personal data from children under the age of 16. By registering to a Bearable account you are required to confirm that you are at least 16 years old.

If Bearable gains actual knowledge that the information has been collected from children under 16, we reserve the right to immediately delete the account and wipe all related information, including health and sensitive data of the user, from our servers.

If you are a parent and learn that your child is using Bearable without your permission or if you have any specific question about data privacy at Bearable, do not hesitate to get in touch with us at [support@bearable.app](mailto:support@bearable.app).

Changes to this Privacy Policy

BEARABLE reserves the right to amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to reflect changes in the law, our data collection and data use practices, the features of Bearable’s services, or advances in technology. Please check this page periodically for changes. If we make a change to this Privacy Policy that, in our sole discretion, is material, we will notify you by posting notice of these changes in this Privacy Policy.

[

](https://apps.apple.com/us/app/bearable-mood-symptoms/id1482581097)

[

](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bearable)

Menu

---------------------------------

[

](https://bearable.app/)

©2024 Bearable Ltd
